Forceps. This is…
止血鉗，這是…
Hanabusa.
花房護士
Mr. Igarashi's reports were on my desk.
五十嵐先生的診斷書在我桌上
-I'm sorry for misplacing them. -It's okay.
-抱歉是我自己亂放 -沒關係
-You may go back now. -Thank you.
-你可以回去了 -好的
Two simultaneous Snipe surgeries were completed at Tojo University.
東城大學同步完成兩台醫狙手術後
-Finished.
-完成
Everything changed.
局面就翻轉了
Lastly, at Dr. Takashina's request,
最後，因應高階醫生的請求
we will introduce 20 new Snipe units to our facilities.
本院決定引進20支醫狙
One unit costs three million yen.
一支要價300萬日圓呢
Eventually, you will all be entrusted to perform surgeries with it.
將來你們也將受託使用醫狙進行手術
I want each of you to follow instructions to prepare for this.
希望每個人遵照指示，做好準備
With Dr. Saeki's approval,
在佐伯教授的允許下
Tojo's promotion of the Snipe
東城大學開始全力推行
was fully underway.
使用醫狙儀器
We've reached the mitral valve.
已到達二尖瓣
Complete.
完成
It's much faster than the Saeki Method
比佐伯式手術快多了
and it's so simple.
也很簡單
The need for skilled surgeons might really be at its end.
需要能幹外科醫生的日子 也許真的屈指可數了
Dr. Takashina got his case data
高階醫生取得病歷數據
and was nearing completion of his Snipe paper.
相關的醫狙論文也接近完稿
But there was still one big problem.
不過，還有一個大問題懸而未決
The name of the author, written in the introduction
寫在論文導言的作者名字
and the name at the end of the person in charge
以及論文末的署名
indicate the most important people involved in research.
就是該項研究的最高負責人
The Impact Factor from a paper
該論文得到的影響因子
is given solely to these two people.
只授予這兩人
In conclusion, the person at the end of the Snipe paper
也就是說，出現在醫狙論文結尾的人
would earn many Impact Factor points
將獲得很高的影響因子
and certainly win the election for Chairman.
當然能贏得理事長的選舉
If the former editor-in-chief, Mr. Kusunoki, is backing you,
如果前任主編楠木先生支持你
I cannot intervene.
那我也無法干涉
I promise to repay you.
我一定會報答你的
I can't publish the paper under your name
我沒辦法把你的名字寫在論文上
as things currently stand.
考慮到目前的情況
If that's the case, then you don't need to worry.
這件事您大可不必擔心
Measures have already been taken.
已經採取因應措施了
The battle over the Snipe paper
醫狙論文的掛名爭奪戰
was nearing its final stage.
已經接近最後階段
All the while, an emergency conference was held
期間，為了一名患者的手術
regarding a new patient's surgery.
醫院召開了緊急會議
Koharu Shimano, seven years old. Transferred from Teika University.
島野小春，現年七歲 是從帝華大學醫院轉過來的患者
She was diagnosed with mitral valve insufficiency.
她被診斷出心臟二尖瓣閉鎖不全
However, the main problem lies in her blood.
但最大的問題是她的血液
Her platelet count is extremely low…
由於血小板過低…
It will be okay.
不會有事的
…making it difficult for her blood to clot.
…她的血液很難凝固
With an allergy to blood transfusion
再加上對輸血有過敏反應
and irregular antibodies,
以及血液裡有不規則抗體
it's nearly impossible to do a blood transfusion.
幾乎不可能對她進行輸血
Open chest surgery would cause heavy blood loss
開胸手術很可能造成大出血
and would kill her immediately.
導致她立即死亡
Therefore, the Saeki Method is out of the question.
因此，不可能進行佐伯式手術
Why did the professor accept a patient like that?
教授為什麼要收這樣的患者？
I have something important to discuss.
教授，我有一件要事想跟您討論
She's a patient I previously cared for at Teika University.
她是我之前在帝華大學醫治過的病患
With repeated heart failures,
由於反覆出現心臟衰竭
she only has a month to live.
只剩下一個月的生命
Can I ask you to perform mitral valve surgery on her at Tojo University?
能不能懇請您在東城大學醫院 為她進行二尖瓣手術？
I will consider it.
我會考慮
But for you, completing the paper
不過，你的首要任務
is your highest priority, right?
是完成論文吧？
Introducing 20 new Snipe units.
藉由引進20支醫狙
I've supported you in increasing case numbers.
我已經幫助你增加新病例了
There's another document.
這裡還有另一份文件
A copy of a patient's chart.
是病患的病歷複本
CHIE KUSUNOKI
（楠木千枝）
It's Mr. Kusunoki's wife.
是楠木先生的太太
Her results came back showing a malignant tumor in her liver.
檢查結果顯示 她的肝臟裡有一顆惡性腫瘤
She's currently undergoing treatment at Teika University
她目前在帝華大學接受治療
with a specialist recommended by Dr. Nishizaki.
主治醫生是西崎教授推薦的專家
It's cutting-edge chemotherapy only available at Teika University.
她接受最先進的化療 是帝華大學獨有的
Mr. Kusunoki is indebted not only to you,
楠木先生不只是欠您人情
but now to Dr. Nishizaki as well.
如今也受到西崎教授的幫助
It means that my paper will be published
也就是說論文都會被刊登
whether it's your name or Dr. Nishizaki's that I put at the end.
不管論文末寫上您或西崎教授的名字
I'm sure you know what that means.
想必您很清楚這代表什麼吧
Won't Dr. Nishizaki help you?
西崎教授不肯幫忙嗎？
Unfortunately,
很可惜
-that's a risk I cannot afford to take. -"That's a risk I cannot afford to take."
-我不能冒這個風險 -“我不能冒這個風險”
Am I right?
我猜對了吧？
Operating to ensure a child's future.
為了孩子的未來進行手術
It's a wonderful thing, isn't it.
這是多麼高尚的事
Very well.
那好吧，把她轉到東城來
Thank you.
謝謝您
One condition.
有一個條件
I'm sure you get it.
你應該知道怎麼做吧
About the paper.
論文的事
I give you my word.
我跟您保證
After verifying her situation,
確認過她的狀況後
I've decided to perform Snipe surgery.
我已經決定用醫狙來做手術
The operating surgeon
執刀醫生是
will be Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Dr. Tokai again?
怎麼又是渡海醫生？
He is skilled, after all. What did you expect?
畢竟他的醫術精湛
Got it, Dr. Tokai?
可以吧，渡海？
I decline.
恕我拒絕
You decline?
居然拒絕了？
The surgery can't be done with the Snipe.
這次手術無法用醫狙來完成
But if there's no other choice and you need my help,
不過如果沒有辦法了 而您執意要我來做
would you instruct me to use the Saeki Method?
能不能讓我進行佐伯式手術呢？
I don't care what you want.
我不管你想怎樣
The professor has found the Saeki Method to be too risky
教授已經說了 使用佐伯式手術風險太高
and has decided on Snipe surgery. Got it? This is an order!
已經決定用醫狙動手術了 聽懂了嗎？這是命令
What's that?
怎麼搞的？
So this isn't Dr. Saeki's surgical department.
所以這裡不是佐伯的外科部
It's Dr. Takashina's, isn't it?
變成了高階的外科部了，對吧？
At the department I know, all of our mitral valve operations
在我所認識的佐伯外科裡 所有二尖瓣手術
are done using the Saeki Method.
採用的都是佐伯式
Nobody was ready to make the switch
這個新玩具剛引進的時候
when you brought that new toy in.
可是沒有人準備轉投它的懷抱
-Toy? -Make the switch?
-玩具？ -轉投它的懷抱？
You're all really something.
你們真了不起
After all those objections you had at first,
剛開始那麼激烈反對
all I hear now is "Snipe."
現在開口閉口都是“醫狙”
You've all done your homework, I see.
看來你們都學得很快
-Shut your mouth, Tokai! -Dr. Tokai…
-渡海，別說了 -渡海醫生…
Taking on difficult operations and succeeding each time.
進行困難的手術 而且一次又一次克服挑戰
That's Dr. Seigo Saeki. That's the Saeki Method.
那才是佐伯清剛的作風 那才是佐伯式手術吧
If you're saying it can't be done with the Saeki Method
要是您說無法用佐伯式動手術
but it would be possible with the Snipe…
但用醫狙卻辦得到…
-You've admitted defeat. -Tokai!
-那就等於認輸了 -渡海！
If you don't need them anymore, give them to me.
要是您不再需要的話，那就給我好了
Your black forceps.
您的黑色止血鉗
Tokai.
渡海
I understand.
我明白了
You have some serious nerve
既然你這麼有膽
mocking me and the black forceps like that.
大肆嘲弄我和黑色止血鉗
I assume you came prepared for the consequences.
想必你也準備好接受後果了
You're no longer needed.
這裡不需要你了
You will not be involved in any surgeries after this.
今後你不能再參與任何手術
You have no right to be here.
你已經沒有資格待在本院
Get out,
請你離開
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
If it's the doctor's orders…
恭敬不如從命
SEISHIRO TOKAI
（渡海征司郎）
Now you're the only one who can operate.
那麼只能由你來當執刀醫生了
Understood?
可以吧？
Yes.
可以
As for the punishment given to Dr. Tokai…
就這樣，渡海醫生得到處分
Pardon me.
打擾了
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Director Moriya asked me to tell you
守屋院長要我轉告你
that you should clean up and be out of here in a month.
在一個月內把東西收拾好離開
They told me to help carry your stuff to the medical office.
他們要我來幫你把東西搬到辦公室
What should I take first?
要從哪裡開始收拾？
Do whatever you want.
隨便你
You're no help.
根本沒幫上忙嘛
Why did you say all that?
為什麼要說那種話？
It's so heavy.
好重
Hey, wait. What's this?
等等，這是什麼
You can take my stuff out too.
也順便幫我搬吧
What?
什麼？
Nekota, wait. What's this about?
請等一下，這是什麼意思？貓田護士
That Dr. Tokai…
那個渡海醫生
He's basically Dr. Saeki's right-hand man.
可以說是佐伯教授的左右手
The surgical department won't last long now with him gone.
他走的話，佐伯外科也撐不久的
Dr. Saeki has dug his own grave, you could say.
佐伯教授可以說是自掘墳墓
This guarantees your landslide victory in the election. In that case…
這樣理事長的選舉 您一定獲得壓倒性勝利，如此一來…
When I win,
要是我勝選
I'll leave you in charge of one of my affiliated hospitals, Mr. Moriya.
守屋院長 我會把旗下一間附屬醫院交給你管理
It would be a great honor! I'll be in your care.
那真是太榮幸了，我任由閣下差遣
-Hanabusa. -Yes?
-花房護士 -是
Give this to Dr. Tokai.
把這個交給渡海醫生
Me?
我去嗎？
Please.
拜託你了
Excuse me.
打擾了
Um, Dr. Tokai…
那個，渡海醫生…
Want some?
要吃嗎？
No, thank you, I'm fine.
不用了，謝謝
This is delicious.
真好吃
Isn't it?
對吧？
I didn't think rice could be so good.
我沒想過白飯這麼美味
They say Japanese bodies are made of rice.
人家說日本人的身體都是白米做的
Forceps?
止血鉗？
Dr. Takashina did countless simulations
高階醫生做了無數次模擬手術
in order to deal with Koharu's hemophilia.
以因應小春的血友病
To prevent hemorrhaging, the incision in the heart
為了避免大出血，在心臟上的切口
must be as small as possible.
必須盡可能地縮小
The standard is 20 millimeters.
標準寬度是20毫米
We'll try 12.
我們嘗試用12毫米
Twelve millimeters.
12毫米
It's the same size as the Snipe's diameter.
跟醫狙的直徑一樣
That's our limit.
已經是極限了
Even one small slip of the finger
哪怕只是有一點差池
will tear the muscle and cause massive bleeding.
都會撕裂心肌，造成大出血
It can be done in theory.
不過，理論上是可行的
We'll operate in one week.
手術將在一週後進行
Perform more tests on her blood coagulation.
再詳細檢查一下凝血功能
-Right. -Okay.
-是 -好的
The truth is…
實不相瞞
there's less than a five-percent success rate.
手術成功率不到5%
Five percent?
5%？
Before I finish my paper,
在完成論文之前
OVER LETHAL DOSE
（超過致命劑量）
we must save her.
我們一定要救活這孩子
No matter the cost.
無論要付出什麼代價
-Soy sauce ramen. -Looks great.
-醬油拉麵 -好好吃的樣子
-Soy sauce chashu ramen. -Thank you.
-醬油叉燒拉麵 -謝謝
-Let's eat. -Please enjoy.
-開動吧 -請享用
So, no matter the results of the operation,
所以無論手術結果如何
your name will appear in the paper?
您的名字都會列在論文上嗎？
Yes. Those were my conditions.
對，這是我附的條件
Don't you think it's funny?
不覺得很有趣嗎？
Elite adults like you would go to such lengths for a single paper.
你們這些菁英人物為了一篇論文 這麼煞費苦心
What we want isn't just the paper.
我們真正想要的不是論文
It's Impact Factor.
而是影響因子
It really is true.
這倒是
For a doctor, the Impact Factor is really like your Michelin stars.
對醫生來說 影響因子媲美米其林星星
This restaurant became famous overnight
這家店拿到第一顆米其林星時
when it received its first star.
一夕間名氣暴增
That's right.
沒錯
But for us, those stars also determine the chairman election.
但對我們來說，這些星星 甚至能決定理事長的選舉結果
That's why I'll do whatever it takes.
所以我會不擇手段拿下
Even if it makes me look bad.
就算要吃相難看也無所謂
The winner takes all.
這場比賽是贏者全拿
It's a good look. Scars and all.
不難看，包括瘡疤在內
TOJO HOSPITAL DR. TOKAI
（東城大學，渡海醫生來電）
-Please excuse me. -Sure.
-抱歉，我接個電話 -好
I have something to ask of you.
我有事想拜託你
Twelve millimeters is impossible.
12毫米不可能做得到
The procedure will damage the surrounding blood vessels.
手術進行時會傷及周圍的血管
Theoretically, it can be done.
理論上是可行的
We have to try.
只能放手一搏了
In the days leading up to Koharu's operation,
隨著小春的手術日期越來越接近
Dr. Takashina began to show his worry.
高階醫生也開始焦慮不安
Don't worry, Koharu.
小春，別擔心
I'll help you get better.
我會治好你的
I promise.
打勾勾
Yeah.
好
Dr. Takashina is amazing.
高階醫生好厲害
He's doing tests, verifications and simulations all day long,
白天做檢查 進行方法驗證和模擬手術
then writing the paper at night, and more testing, on his own.
晚上寫論文，然後又自己做更多測試
When does he sleep?
他哪有時間睡覺啊？
I respect him, honestly.
老實說，我很佩服他
At first, I thought he was just a smart-ass.
剛開始覺得他很自作聰明
-But he's way tougher than both of us. -You're right.
-但其實他比我們更頑強 -你說得對
Unlike that sloth Tokai over there.
跟懶散的渡海醫生完全不一樣
That's supposed to be our nap room.
那個房間本來是我們的休息室
You're right.
對啊
Which room?
哪一間病房？
This way!
這邊
-What happened? -Doctor.
-怎麼回事？ -醫生
Sudden heart failure.
急性心臟衰竭
-We need oxygen and a diuretic. -Okay.
-準備氧氣和利尿劑 -是
-Mask, please. -Take over.
-氧氣面罩 -我來
-You'll be okay. -Oxygen, hurry.
-沒事的 -快點給氧
Acute MR.
是急性MR
MITRAL REGURGITATION
（二尖瓣閉鎖不全）
He needs emergency surgery.
需要緊急動手術
-We'll use the Snipe. -Right.
-用醫狙吧 -好的
Take him to OR one.
送去第一手術室
I've contacted the head nurse.
我聯絡護士長了
-Right. -Okay.
-好的 -好
I've brought the Snipe.
醫狙拿來了
Let's take a look at the mitral valve with ultrasound.
-先用超音波檢查一下二尖瓣 -是
On screen.
在螢幕上了
Preparing to insert the Snipe.
準備插入醫狙
Wait. I can see vegetation on the mitral valve.
等一下，二尖瓣上有贅生物
VEGETATION = BACTERIAL MASS
（贅生物，細菌形成的團塊）
If we use an artificial valve, the bacteria will get damaged and spread.
如果使用人工瓣膜 會破壞團塊，造成細菌擴散
-We can't use the Snipe. -Then what should we do?
-那就不能使用醫狙了 -那該怎麼辦？
The large arteries have calcified. We can't stop the heart.
大動脈鈣化，不能讓心跳暫停
We must use the Saeki Method.
只能用佐伯式手術法了
Don't be absurd, Dr. Saeki isn't here today!
別胡說了，佐伯醫生今天不在院裡
Um, this patient… is Dr. Tokai's patient.
這位患者是渡海醫生負責的
We must call him. He's the only one.
我們必須去通知他，只能靠他了
-Go now! -Right.
-麻煩你了 -是
We'll perform a central incision. Get the heart-lung machine.
直接從正中開胸，準備人工心肺機
-Understood. -Right.
-明白 -好的
-Take over. -Miyamoto, take this.
-你來 -宮元，這個拿走
Excuse me, Dr. Tokai!
打擾了，渡海醫生！
There has been an emergency in Operating Room one.
第一手術室在進行二尖瓣緊急手術
You have to come with me.
請跟我去一趟
I decline.
我拒絕
What?
什麼？
He won't come?
他不肯來嗎？
He says it's because he was ordered not to get involved by the doctor.
對，他說是教授禁止他再參與手術
-Can you put him on the line for me? -Okay.
-請渡海醫生過來聽電話 -好
Excuse me…
不好意思…
I'll put it on speaker.
我開擴音好了
Dr. Tokai, can you hear me? Dr. Tokai?
渡海醫生，聽得到嗎？渡海醫生？
Be quiet. It's the middle of the night.
小聲一點，現在是大半夜
It's Mr. Murakami from Room 314.
是314號病房的村上先生
He's your patient.
他是您的病患
He needs mitral valve surgery now. But we can't use the Snipe.
現在需要立刻做二尖瓣手術 但我們不能用醫狙
We must perform the Saeki Method. We need you.
只能做佐伯式手術 您能過來一趟嗎？
I told you. The doctor ordered me not to operate.
我都說了，教授不准我再參與手術
But…
但是…
You're the only one who can help this patient.
現在只有您能救他了
-Blood pressure 50. -He's in septic shock.
-血壓50 -出現敗血性休克
-Give him norepinephrine. -Okay.
-注射正腎上腺素 -是
Dr. Tokai. I'm begging you to come.
渡海醫生，求求您快過來吧
Please, Dr. Tokai.
拜託了，渡海醫生
-Saline, hurry! -Right.
-生理食鹽水，快點 -是
Body temperature is at 39 degrees Celsius.
體溫升高到攝氏39度了
The vegetation is peeling off.
贅生物快要脫落了
We must perform the Saeki Method now.
必須立刻進行佐伯式手術
At this rate clumps of bacteria will spread through the body.
這樣下去，細菌團塊會擴散到全身
We're out of time.
沒時間了
Dr. Saeki…
佐伯教授…
The head nurse…
護士長…
-Miyamoto, a gown. -Okay.
-宮元，手術服 -是
The doctor just returned from his seminar and rushed over to assist us.
教授剛結束研討會回來 立刻就趕過來了
-Take over. -Okay.
-交給你 -是
Fill me in.
報告狀況
Acute MR from infective endocarditis.
是感染性心內膜炎造成的急性MR
And vegetation on the mitral valve.
二尖瓣上還有贅生物
-That's why you can't use the Snipe. -Yes, that's correct.
-所以無法用醫狙 -對，沒錯
We'll remove the infected area and repair the valves.
那麼切除感染部位 並進行修補二尖瓣手術
Pardon me.
借過
-Scalpel. -Clear the field.
-手術刀 -清理視野
-Where are those suctions? -Sorry. Coming right away.
-抽吸器呢？ -抱歉，馬上來
No need.
沒那個必要
My finger will guide me.
我的手指會指引我
The Saeki Method.
是佐伯式
Metz.
手術剪
-Black forceps. -Right.
-黑色止血鉗 -是
Incredible.
好厲害
This man really is a god.
這個人真的太神了
Compared to Dr. Tokai,
比起渡海醫生…
He's…
他…
Professor!
教授
Thank you so much.
真的非常感謝您
Sorry for the commotion.
抱歉造成這麼多混亂
We tried to call Dr. Tokai, but…
我們本來想找渡海醫生，但…
I told him to stay out of it.
我說過不准他參與手術
There's no problem.
不要緊
These were unforeseen circumstances.
這是突發狀況
You did everything you could.
你已經盡力了
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
Treatment doesn't always go according to simulations.
醫療未必總會和模擬手術完全一樣
If he's going to follow the doctor's orders now,
如果他那麼遵從教授的指示
I wish he would have agreed to do Koharu's operation.
我倒希望他也能同意替小春做手術
Dr. Tokai said he has never let a patient die.
渡海醫生說 他不曾讓病人死在手術台上
I was hopeful that Dr. Tokai
所以我本來也希望渡海醫生
could take care of Koharu's Snipe surgery as well.
能負責用醫狙替小春動手術
Why did he decline that one order?
他為什麼會拒絕呢？
Isn't that why?
不就是因為這樣嗎？
What?
什麼？
Isn't that why Dr. Tokai said no?
正是因為這樣 渡海醫生才拒絕的吧？
MOM
（媽媽）
What is it?
什麼事？
What's with you? Someone sounds sleepy.
怎麼了？ 聽起來很睏的樣子
Are you eating well?
有好好吃飯嗎？
Every day.
每天都有
Japanese bodies are made out of rice.
日本人的身體都是米飯做的哦
How many times are you going to say that? What do you want?
這句話你要說多少遍？ 到底有什麼事？
I sent some for you to give to Dr. Saeki as well.
我寄了一些要你轉送給佐伯醫生
What?
什麼？
He's taken good care of both my husband and my son.
我丈夫和兒子都承蒙他的照顧啊
Make sure he gets it, will you?
一定要好好交給他，知道嗎？
-Bye! -Hey, wait!
-再見 -等等
He's good.
他好厲害
He sure is. I bet you could do it too.
是啊，你一定也可以
Hello, Koharu.
小春，你好
-Hello.
-你好
-Do you like soccer? -Yes.
-你喜歡足球嗎？ -喜歡
I'll be able to play soon, they said.
他們說我很快就能踢球了
Dr. Takashina promised to make me all better.
高階醫生答應會治好我
That's great.
這樣啊
When your surgery is done and you're all better,
那等你做完手術，身體復原了
let's play soccer with Dr. Takashina.
我們一起跟高階醫生踢足球吧
Yeah.
好
So, as soon as the child's operation is finished you'll have the paper, right?
所以等那個孩子的手術完成後 你就會拿到論文了吧？
Yes. I'm sure you'll be pleased.
對，你一定會很滿意
Isn't it a dangerous operation?
這項手術不是很危險嗎？
If it fails,
如果失敗了
Dr. Takashina will have to take responsibility as operating surgeon.
執刀的高階醫生也必須負責
The paper is nearly complete.
論文就快完成了
And so is Dr. Takashina's role.
他扮演的角色也是
If it fails,
失敗的話
we will just remove Dr. Takashina's name.
就把高階的名字從論文裡刪除
RICE
（白米）
Why do you have so much rice?
怎麼有這麼多袋米啊？
Don't touch it.
別碰
Sorry.
抱歉
Koharu would die of blood loss within 24 hours of surgery.
小春會在手術後24小時失血而死
I'll help you get better.
我會治好你的
I promise.
打勾勾
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
You're almost done with the paper, right?
論文快寫好了吧？
If you are, I don't see the need for doing this surgery.
那樣的話 我看不出做這次手術有什麼意義
It is true that whether we fail or succeed,
確實，不管手術成功或失敗
it will not affect our seniors.
都不會影響高層
They only care about my paper.
他們只對我的論文感興趣
I'm fully aware of it, too.
這點我也很清楚
But this surgery…
但是這個手術…
Koharu was born with a deficient mitral valve
小春一出生就有二尖瓣功能不全
and I've seen her in pain.
我親眼看過她飽受痛苦的樣子
As hard as I tried, I wasn't able to give her the help she needed.
不管我再怎麼努力，還是幫不了她
The reason I first took an interest in the Snipe
我最初對醫狙這個儀器有興趣
was my hope to save Koharu.
就是希望能幫助小春
The Snipe exists because of her.
因為那孩子，才會有醫狙的
After bowing down and begging the professor,
我跟教授卑躬屈膝之後
I was able to bring it to Japan.
總算能把它引進日本
This time, betraying the professor and swearing loyalty to the enemy,
這次我背叛了我的教授，向敵人輸誠
I've finally made it to the deciding moment.
才終於能走到動手術這一步
If I can't save her,
要是救不了那個孩子
neither the Snipe nor the paper will be complete.
醫狙和論文都無法完成
I've finally made it this far.
我已經走了這麼遠
I've practiced the operation 30 times.
做了30次模擬手術
And all 30 times,
但整整30次
I killed her.
我都害她沒命
While it's feasible in theory,
就算理論上可行
with my current skill,
但是憑我現在的技術
it's impossible!
根本不可能成功！
I thought if we had the Snipe,
我以為只要有醫狙這項工具
if we had the newest technology,
只要有最新的科技
we would be able to save her.
我就可以救她
Koharu is counting on me. She believes in me.
小春指望我，她對我有信心
I promised…
因為我們說好了
I would save her.
我會救她
But as things are, I may not be able to save her.
但是現實狀況是我恐怕無能為力
I might end up…
最後可能還是會
taking her life.
害她喪命
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Use the Snipe.
請你使用醫狙
And help me.
幫助我吧
That's some excuse.
好冗長的理由
Why don't you kill her?
怎麼不乾脆殺死她？
Or how about…
或者是…
you die yourself?
你自己去死一死算了？
It's impossible with that Snipe.
用醫狙本來就不可能成功
Move it.
礙事
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Why did you say it's impossible?
為什麼你說用醫狙做不到？
Do you mean to say
你的意思是
that even in your hands, the Snipe would still fail?
使用醫狙的話 就算由你操作也會失敗嗎？
No matter a surgeon's skill,
無論外科醫生的醫術多精湛
you can't operate with a dull knife.
用一把鈍刀還是無法動手術
The Snipe's blueprints. Why do you have these?
醫狙的設計圖，你怎麼會有這個？
The issue is that the body of that thing is too large.
這東西的缺點是體積笨重
Those are Koharu's CT scans.
這些是小春的電腦斷層掃描
If we don't want to damage the veins, we'll have to go through them.
如果不能傷到血管 就只能從血管穿過去了
Through the veins?
穿過血管？
With a catheter?
用導管嗎？
If we enter the veins through her thighs, we'll arrive at the heart.
如果從大腿通過靜脈 的確是可以到達心臟
But that route will lead us to the right atrium.
但這個路徑會通往右心房
RIGHT ATRIUM
（右心室）
The mitral valve is near the left atrium.
二尖瓣靠近的是左心室
LEFT ATRIUM MITRAL VALVE
（二尖瓣）
A catheter can't go through the septum wall.
導管無法突破中膈
That's why the Snipe was developed to reach the mitral valve directly.
所以才研發了 可直接到達二尖瓣的醫狙
-Using a catheter is old-fashioned now. -Listen to me.
-導管已經是過時的作法了 -所以
We'll attach the Snipe…
我們就把醫狙…
…to the catheter.
…跟導管相連不就好了
The Snipe's artificial valve system on a catheter?
把人工瓣膜系統裝在導管上嗎？
There's a small tear in her septum wall.
她的心室中膈有個小破洞
We'll go through there.
從那裡穿過去
If we can get to the mitral valve, we'll only have to replace the valve.
如果能從那裡到達二尖瓣 再置換瓣膜就可以了
Using a catheter like that…
用這種方式使用導管…
What's the point of new technology if it can't be used?
如果新技術不能加以運用 還有什麼意義？
Old methods have their strengths.
傳統方法還是有優點的
Medicine isn't always about progress alone.
醫療的目標不只是一味求進步
But there's still one problem.
但還有一個問題
A complicated operation like this…
這麼複雜的手術…
You're the only one who can do it.
只有你可以勝任
I'm not allowed to.
我被下禁令了
You heard what the doctor told me.
你也聽到教授的話了
So that's what this is.
原來是這樣
From the very start,
你從一開始
you wanted to be the operating surgeon.
就打算當執刀醫生吧？
What will you do?
你要怎麼做？
I have something to talk to you about, professor.
教授，有一件事我想跟您商量一下
I would like to request that Dr. Tokai
我提議由渡海醫生
perform Koharu's Snipe surgery.
負責小春的醫狙手術
Please permit him to return to the operating room.
請允許他重返手術室
Bowing your head for a man like that…
你竟然會為了那種男人低頭…
Wasn't it you who wanted him out?
你不是想趕走他嗎？
Please permit Dr. Tokai to be the operating surgeon.
請您允許由渡海醫生來執刀
It's fine by me.
我無所謂
It was me, after all,
畢竟是我
who ordered him to operate with the Snipe in the first place.
一開始就要他使用醫狙來動手術
Dr. Tokai will do the surgery.
所以由渡海醫生執刀
There should be no issue.
沒有什麼問題
In medicine, having the right tools is a necessity.
在醫療上，合適的工具不可或缺
But so is having skill.
但技術也一樣重要
Be there to assist him and give him your support.
就由你來當助手協助渡海
Of course, I will.
當然，我很樂意
I promise we will succeed.
我保證會讓手術成功
The fateful day finally arrived.
就這樣，決定性的日子到了
-Has it started? -Soon.
-開始了嗎？ -快了
We will now perform off-pump mitral valve surgery using the new Snipe.
接下來使用醫狙這樣新器械 進行非體外循環二尖瓣手術
-Ultrasound. -Here.
-超音波 -來了
-Bring that closer. -Okay.
-靠近一點 -是
Okay.
好了
Dr. Tokai is really the operating surgeon?
真的是渡海執刀？
-Guidewire. -Here.
-導線 -這裡
Snipe preparations complete.
醫狙已準備就緒
-New Snipe, please. -Okay.
-新型醫狙 -是
I'm going in.
要插入了
It's in. Take over.
進去了，你來
-Catheter. -Here.
-導管 -是
They attached the Snipe's artificial valve system to the tip of a catheter.
他們把醫狙的人工瓣膜置換系統 接在導管上
That should help prevent hemorrhaging.
這樣應該能避免大出血
Did Tokai ask you to hand over the Snipe blueprints?
渡海跟你要了醫狙的設計圖嗎？
I was only helping to make this surgery a success.
我只是為了這場手術能夠成功
Arriving at the right atrium soon.
即將到達右心室
RIGHT ATRIUM
（右心室）
Already in the right atrium?
已經到右心室了？
Who knew he could use a catheter as skillfully as that?
誰想得到他 連操作導管的技術也是一流的？
We reached the right atrium.
已到達右心室
They're in.
到了
Next is the hard part.
下一步才是最困難的
They'll have to break through the wall that connects to the left atrium.
他們必須穿透與左心室相連的中膈
It seems they planned on passing through a small hole in the patient's heart,
他們似乎打算 從患者心室中膈上的小破洞穿過去
but even a slight miscalculation could cause a blockage
但是只要位置稍有偏差 就會造成傳導阻滯
and lead to cardiac abnormalities.
最終導致心臟出現異常
And in this case, even sudden death.
甚至可能造成病患猝死
Can they really push it through something so narrow?
他們真的能通過這麼窄的路徑嗎？
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Proceed through the septum wall
聽我的提示
on my signal.
來穿透心室中膈
When the hole is at its widest point…
在中膈的小洞擴張到最大時…
I'll give the signal.
我會給你提示
SEPTUM - MITRAL VALVE
（心室中膈，二尖瓣）
Not yet.
還沒有
Now!
就是現在
We're through.
穿過去了
SEPTUM - MITRAL VALVE
（心室中膈，二尖瓣）
We're in the left atrium.
到達左心室了
-Wow! -They did it!
-天啊 -他們成功了！
On top of Dr. Tokai's skills,
技術精湛的渡海醫生
Dr. Takashina has the brains and knows Koharu's condition best.
搭配熟知小春病況的智囊團高階醫生
The best team.
真是最佳拍檔
All right. Now, to replace the valve.
好了，現在要置換瓣膜了
We're at the mitral valve.
已到達二尖瓣
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Valve replacement complete.
人工瓣膜置換完成
The valve is functioning!
瓣膜已正常運作
-Yes! -Amazing!
-好耶！ -太棒了！
Amazing!
太好了！
They did it.
他們成功了！
I'll finish up.
我來收尾吧
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Thank you.
謝謝你
We'll close up the septum hole.
接下來修補中膈缺損
-Take over. -Okay.
-你來接手 -是
What you said to me before, is that how you really feel?
你之前跟我說的那些話是真心的嗎？
If you don't need them anymore, give them to me.
要是您不再需要的話，那就給我好了
Your black forceps.
您的黑色止血鉗
Tojo University will be seeing significant growth.
東城大學今後還會不斷壯大
This is the transitional period.
目前是過渡期
You don't need to worry.
你不必擔憂
I just ask that you continue to support me.
你只需要繼續支持我就行了
Believe in me.
對我有信心
I give you my deepest gratitude.
這次真的非常感謝您
Do you understand it now? It's more than just Teika's research.
現在你明白了吧？ 這不只是帝華大學的研究
Because of its practical use at Tojo University,
正是因為在東城大學進行了實際操作
the Snipe's potential has been realized.
醫狙的潛力才能完全發揮
If we work together,
要是我們合作
your ideal world
你理想中
where healthcare is provided equally to everyone
人人都可公平享受醫療的世界
can become a reality.
就可以成真
I will definitely make it work.
我一定會讓它實現
Believe in me.
相信我吧
I'll be looking forward to the paper.
我很期待看到你的論文
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Why is it that you're loyal only to Dr. Saeki
你為什麼只對佐伯教授一個
and no one else?
那麼忠心耿耿呢？
Do you trust him that much?
你就那麼信任他嗎？
Well, it doesn't matter.
算了，不重要
So what will it be this time?
這次有什麼要求？
I'm ready to pay what you ask.
無論多少我都可以付給你
I'll lend it to you.
先欠著
What?
什麼？
Next time, it won't be money
下次我會要你付出
that I'll ask you to pay with.
金錢以外的代價
Don't believe him.
別相信他
Dr. Seigo Saeki.
佐伯清剛教授
When he feels threatened,
當他感覺到受威脅時
that man won't hesitate to cut ties with anyone
那傢伙會為了利益毫不猶豫
as he sees fit.
跟對方切割
Anyone at all.
不管對方是誰
Even his closest allies.
就算是親近的同僚也不例外
Another fateful day arrived.
就這樣，最重要的日子又來臨了
JAPAN SURGICAL JOURNAL
（《日本外科期刊》）
Forgive me. But you must understand.
非常抱歉，還請您理解
Whatever punishment you choose to give me
無論給我什麼處分
I will accept.
我都會接受
I'll be excused now.
我先出去了
So everything is going according to your original plan?
一切都按照您的計畫完成了嗎？
I'm impressed.
真佩服啊
Unfortunately, that's a risk I cannot afford to take.
很可惜，我不能冒這個風險
But I'm sure Dr. Saeki will accept.
但我相信佐伯教授應該會接受
Just pretend to go along with their proposal.
你就假意附和他們的提議
Use them to your heart's desire.
利用他們滿足你的渴望
If the operation succeeds, we'll have a great case in our hands.
手術如果成功 我們也可以獲得珍貴的病例
With that, you'll be ready to finish the paper.
這樣一來，你也可以完成論文
The Impact Factor will go to Dr. Nishizaki,
影響因子會授予佐伯教授
and of course, to me.
當然也包括我
That's it.
就這樣
I have no more use for Tojo.
我對東城來說沒利用價值了
There's an infection in her heart's septum.
心臟出現感染
When the kid leaves, so do you.
帶著這孩子滾出去
May I use the Darwin?
我可以用達爾文嗎？
Show them the real strength of Teika University.
讓他們看看帝華大學的實力
It's showtime.
好戲登場了
Let's go.
我們走
Koharu has always believed in you, Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生，小春一直很信任你
You said we can change the rules.
你說過我們可以改變規則
The Darwin research can't be taken from us.
我們的達爾文研究計畫不能被奪走
Dr. Takashina is off the team.
高階醫生離開團隊了
Move it!
讓開！
I want to change the world of Japanese medicine.
我想改變日本醫藥界
Aren't things working out well for you?
您的運氣真好…
Pretty words alone can't save a single life.
光靠說好聽話，救不了人命
This is nothing.
當然有辦法完成
Watch me do it.
好好看我怎麼做
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：莊雅婷